{
    "questions" : [
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "36_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Why are your clothes so wet? Is it raining outside?\nMan : Yes, it's raining suddenly when I'm coming home.\nWoman : Please wipe it with this first.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "36_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : Mr. Sumi, here it is. Did you enjoy the trip.\nWoman : Yes, but I'm a little tired because I've been on the plane for a long time. Did you wait a long time?\nMan : No. Give me the bag I'll take.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "36_3_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : As a result of the survey of the purpose of college education for college students, the most respondents were ‘to get a good job’, followed by ‘development of abilities’ and ‘Acquiring knowledge’. This seems to reflect students' concerns about the reality that the progress rate has increased but the employment rate has decreased.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어질 수 있는 말을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "4. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  야유회를 다녀왔군요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  가까운 곳으로 갔어요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  옷을 따뜻하게 입고 가세요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  추울 때는 집에서 쉬곤 해요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The weather keeps getting cold these days. I heard that the temperature will drop more tomorrow.\nMan : I have to go to the picnic tomorrow, but I'm worried.\nWoman : I often rest at home when it's cold.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  옷을 따뜻하게 입고 가세요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어질 수 있는 말을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "5.",
            "option_1"      : "①  살아 보니 소음이 너무 심하더라고",
            "option_2"      : "②  혼자 사는 것보다 둘이 사는 게 좋았어",
            "option_3"      : "③  지금 집은 학교와 가까워서 편하고 좋아",
            "option_4"      : "④  부동산에 가서 알아보는 게 좋을 것 같아서",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I'm looking for a new house to move to these days.\nMan : Why? You said you liked the house you live in now.\nWomanb: When I live, the noise was too loud.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  살아 보니 소음이 너무 심하더라고",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어질 수 있는 말을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "6. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  그래?텐트만 사면 되겠네",
            "option_2"      : "②  그래도 자세히 알아봐야겠다",
            "option_3"      : "③  그래?미리 알았으면 좋았을걸",
            "option_4"      : "④  그래도 텐트는 치기 힘들겠다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I'm looking for a new house to move to these days.\nMan : Why? You said you liked the house you live in now.\nWoman : When I live, the noise was too loud.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  그래?미리 알았으면 좋았을걸",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어질 수 있는 말을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "7.",
            "option_1"      : "①  분위기가 카페처럼 참 좋네요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  사무실 옆에 카페가 있으면 좋아요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  집중이 안 되면 카페에서 해 보세요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  전 편안하면 일이 더 잘 될 것 같아요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : There are many companies these days that change the office atmosphere as comfortably as a cafe. It would be delicious to work if you work in such a place.\nMan : I don't think I can concentrate on my work.\nWoman : I think things will be better if I'm comfortable.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  전 편안하면 일이 더 잘 될 것 같아요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어질 수 있는 말을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "8. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  연수 다녀와서 뵙겠습니다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  지난번에 제가 미리 말씀드렸습니다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  개인 사정이 생기면 말씀드리겠습니다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  저도 정말 가고 싶지만 힘들 것 같습니다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : I, boss, I don't think I can go because of the overseas training and personal reasons you mentioned last time.\nWoman : Is that so? It's a good idea, but let's think about it again.\nMan : I really want to go too, but I think it's going to be hard.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  저도 정말 가고 싶지만 힘들 것 같습니다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "9. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  외식하러 갈 식당을 예약한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  퇴근을 하고 약속 장소로 간다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  남편을 만나러 회사 앞으로 간다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  아이들을 데리고 회사 앞으로 간다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman :  Hello? Do you want to eat out with the kids today? You know the Chinese restaurant we often go to.\nMan : good But you have to make a reservation for that restaurant.\nWoman : Yes, I'm going to ask you.\nMan : Is that so? Then I'll be there right after work, so I'll see you at seven.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  외식하러 갈 식당을 예약한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {"sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오",
         "question"      : "10. ",
         "option_1"      : "①  다른 볼일을 보러 간다.",
         "option_2"      : "②  병원 진료 접수를 한다.",
         "option_3"      : "③  병원에 앉아서 기다린다.",
         "option_4"      : "④  진찰을 받으러 들어간다.",
         "detail"        : "Woman : There are a lot of patients today. Do I have to wait a lot?\nMan : Yes, it's the change of seasons. I think you should wait for an hour.\nWoman : Can I register it now and go out?\nMan : Yes, take a look at the work and come on time.",
         "correctAnswer" : "②  병원 진료 접수를 한다.",
         "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오",
      "question"      : "11.",
      "option_1"      : "①  책자에서 커튼을 고른다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  집에서 거실 커튼을 단다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  커튼을 사러 가게에 간다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  커튼을 사서 집에 가져간다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : I'd like to change the curtains in my house.\nMan : Come this way and see. There are also a lot of books, so please take a look.\nWoman : Well....... I don't really like anything in the store, so I need to take a look at the brochure.\nMan : Then sit down and watch it slowly. If you like anything, take it to your house. I'll go and put it on.",
      "correctAnswer" : "①  책자에서 커튼을 고른다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오",
      "question"      : "12. ",
      "option_1"      : "①  직원 교육 일정을 짠다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  특강 강사를 모시러 간다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  특강했던 강사에게 연락한다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  교육 받을 장소를 알아본다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : Manager Kim, did you have the staff training schedule for next month?\nMan: Yes, the schedule is all set and I think the location will be confirmed soon. But I have a special lecture.I'm worried because I can't find someone to give it to me.\nWoman : I'll look into that. You can serve him again last time.It's the same\nMan : Okay. Then I'll report it to you as soon as the place is confirmed.",
      "correctAnswer" : "③  특강했던 강사에게 연락한다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [13~16]다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "13.",
      "option_1"      : "①  남자는 이 프로그램에 만족해 한다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  이 프로그램은 다시 가면 할인해 준다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  이 프로그램은 예약해야 참여할 수 있다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  여자는 이번 달에 이 프로그램에 참가할 것이다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : Did you have a good time in the natural ecology experience?\nMan : Yes. There is a program that departs every weekend. Again when you get a chance I want to go.\nWoman : Is that so? I want to go too, but I don't have time until this month.\nMan : Then go there even when you're on vacation. It's cheaper if you make a reservation in advance.",
      "correctAnswer" : "①  남자는 이 프로그램에 만족해 한다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [13~16]다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "14.",
      "option_1"      : "①  밤에는 난방 기구를 사용할 수 없다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  9시 이후에는 모든 전기 제품을 끈다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  사무실은 일정 온도를 유지해야 한다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  점심시간에는 엘리베이터가 운행되지 않는다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : I'd like to inform you. We ask for your cooperation to save energy in our company. Please keep the heating temperature in the office at 18 degrees and turn off the electrical appliances that you don't use at lunchtime. The elevator will not operate after 9 p.m., so please do not make any mistakes in this point.",
      "correctAnswer" : "③  사무실은 일정 온도를 유지해야 한다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [13~16]다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "15.",
      "option_1"      : "①  맞춤형 순찰제도는 작년부터 실시되었다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  이 제도를 도입한 후 범죄율이 감소하였다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  맞춤형 순찰제도는 전국에서 시행되고 있다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  주민들이 경찰관과 함께 담당 구역을 순찰한다.",
      "detail"        : "Man : Inju City has introduced a customized patrol system since last April. This is a system that designates police officers in charge for each district. We put the police officer's photos and contact information on the district bulletin board so that residents can contact them 24 hours a day. After six months of introduction, the crime rate has been reduced by nearly half, and a plan is being considered to expand this system to other areas.",
      "correctAnswer" : "②  이 제도를 도입한 후 범죄율이 감소하였다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [13~16]다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "16.",
      "option_1"      : "①  시장의 카페에서 다양한 도시락을 판다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  이 시장을 관광지로 알리려고 홍보했다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  시장이 인기를 끌자 도시락 카페가 생겼다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  이 시장에서는 음식을 골라먹는 재미가 있다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : This is a traditional market in Seoul, which is gaining popularity as a new tourist destination. Shall we listen to the secret of popularity from the president of the merchant association who was with us?\nMan : The secret is the 'lunch box cafe'. Among the foods sold at the market, I put what suits my taste in my lunch box and eat it at this cafe. It's like a picnic. As this became known through word of mouth, our market became famous. Now it has become a tourist destination that is visited not only by Koreans but also by foreigners.",
      "correctAnswer" : "②  이 시장을 관광지로 알리려고 홍보했다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [17~20]다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "17.",
      "option_1"      : "①  컴퓨터를 꼭 학원에서 배울 필요는 없다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  컴퓨터를 더 배워 두면 경쟁력이 커진다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  컴퓨터는 자기가 필요한 만큼만 배우면 된다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  컴퓨터 학원은 자격증을 딸 때까지 가야 한다.",
      "detail"        : "Man : Sumi, why don't you go to computer academy these days?\nWoman : I think this is enough. Even if you use only what you know now, the computer I don't think there will be any hard work because I can't do it. But I have to go to more academy.I wondered if there was a need.\nMan : But wouldn't it be better to learn something in depth? Especially these days in a competitive society The stronger your professionalism, the more competitive you become.",
      "correctAnswer" : "②  컴퓨터를 더 배워 두면 경쟁력이 커진다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [17~20]다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "18.",
      "option_1"      : "①  칭찬을 받으면 일할 의욕이 높아진다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  칭찬을 받으려면 거절하지 말아야 한다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  칭찬을 받으면 그 말을 의식해서 행동하게 된다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  칭찬을 받으면 다른 사람도 칭찬해 줘야 한다.",
      "detail"        : "Man : Sumi, what kind of compliments did you give to your club juniors a while ago?\nWoman : Why? The junior is in charge of all the club work and someone else helps.I've never said no when I needed it. It's commendable.\nMan : Is that so? But if my junior gets that kind of compliment, I can't do it even if I want to refuse it later. I paid attention to the compliment, so I thought I had to do what he said. It works",
      "correctAnswer" : "③  칭찬을 받으면 그 말을 의식해서 행동하게 된다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [17~20]다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "19.",
      "option_1"      : "①  커피숍 주인은 손님을 더 배려해야 한다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  커피 값에 공간을 이용하는 비용이 들어 있다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  커피숍에 장시간 있는 것은 영업에 방해가 된다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  커피숍 공간을 다양하게 이용할 수 있게 해야 한다.",
      "detail"        : "Man: Uh, there are no seats in the library. Shall we study at a coffee shop? Woman: Will it still be okay? I have to stay for quite a long time, but I'm sorry for the owner.\nMan : Well, I don't think it's going to be a problem. The coffee shop is originally a story. Aren't you able to take full use of space while reading books? A minister We're paying for it for coffee.\nWoman : But you should think about other customers and get up moderately.",
      "correctAnswer" : "②  커피 값에 공간을 이용하는 비용이 들어 있다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [17~20]다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오.",
      "question"      : "20.",
      "option_1"      : "①  웃음으로 서로의 관계를 회복해야 한다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  화해하고 싶으면 먼저 나를 되돌아봐야 한다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  상대방의 웃음을 보면 화해를 먼저 해야 한다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  화해하려면 상대방의 행동을 미리 살펴야 한다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : Teacher Choi, you published a book called 'Technology of harm' this time. What is the most important part of the book?\nMan : If you want to make up, tell them talk about me. In many cases, people only repeat the other person's words and actions when they try to reconcile. This doesn't help with relationship recovery at all. Rather, it has a bad effect. Look at my words and actions first and say it. You will be able to see the bright smile of the other person.",
      "correctAnswer" : "②  화해하고 싶으면 먼저 나를 되돌아봐야 한다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [21~22]다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
      "question"      : "21.",
      "option_1"      : "①  진정한 독립은 경제적 독립이다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  가족은 함께 생활하는 것이 좋다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  누구나 자신만의 공간이 필요하다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  독립해 사는 것이 좋은 것만은 아니다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : You would be nice. Because I live alone I want to be independent, but my dad is so conservative that I can't let him do it. I'm over 20 years old.\nMan : I heard that your dad especially loves you because you're the youngest? And it's easy to go around because the company is close to home. Why do you want to come out like that?\nWoman : It's close, but the traffic is inconvenient, so it takes a lot of time, and I want to have my own space. But no matter how much I tell you, it's no use.\nMan : There are many times when it's hard to live alone. You have to do all the laundry, washing the dishes, and things you didn't care about until now. It costs a lot of living. And I live alone, so I wake up late and don't eat well.",
      "correctAnswer" : "④  독립해 사는 것이 좋은 것만은 아니다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [21~22]다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
      "question"      : "22.",
      "option_1"      : "①  여자는 아빠와의 사이가 좋지 않다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  여자는 집안일로 스트레스를 받고 있다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  여자의 아버지는 딸의 독립을 반대한다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  여자는 회사가 멀어서 독립하고 싶어한다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : You would be nice. Because I live alone I want to be independent, but my dad is so conservative that I can't let him do it. I'm over 20 years old.\nMan : I heard that your dad especially loves you because you're the youngest? And it's easy to go around because the company is close to home. Why do you want to come out like that?\nWoman : It's close, but the traffic is inconvenient, so it takes a lot of time, and I want to have my own space. But no matter how much I tell you, it's no use.\nMan : There are many times when it's hard to live alone. You have to do all the laundry, washing the dishes, and things you didn't care about until now. It costs a lot of living. And I live alone, so I wake up late and don't eat well.",
      "correctAnswer" : "③  여자의 아버지는 딸의 독립을 반대한다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [23~24]다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
      "question"      : "23.남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
      "option_1"      : "①  잡 마켓 이용을 제안하고 있다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  직장 내의 각 부서를 설명하고 있다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  잡 마켓 이용 경험을 소개하고 있다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  상사의 문제점에 대해 이야기하고 있다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman: How is your company life, Young-woo? I'm having a hard time because my work doesn't fit.\nMan : Is that so? Then why don't you change the department?' There's a job market. Department move It's about the employees who want to promote themselves directly to the desired department.\nWoman : I heard that there is such a thing, but it's a bit burdensome to use it.I can't even notice the manager.\nMan : Don't think so. The company also recommends using it, so use it.I heard that the employees are also satisfied.",
      "correctAnswer" : "①  잡 마켓 이용을 제안하고 있다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [23~24]다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
      "question"      : "24.들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
      "option_1"      : "①  여자는 일하고 있는 부서에 만족해 한다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  잡 마켓은 회사를 홍보하기 위해 만들었다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  잡 마켓은 상사의 허락이 있어야 이용한다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  직원들은 적성에 맞는 부서로 옮길 기회가 있다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman: How is your company life, Young-woo? I'm having a hard time because my work doesn't fit.\nMan : Is that so? Then why don't you change the department?' There's a job market. Department move It's about the employees who want to promote themselves directly to the desired department.\nWoman : I heard that there is such a thing, but it's a bit burdensome to use it.I can't even notice the manager.\nMan : Don't think so. The company also recommends using it, so use it.I heard that the employees are also satisfied.",
      "correctAnswer" : "④  직원들은 적성에 맞는 부서로 옮길 기회가 있다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [25~26]다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
      "question"      : "25.남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
      "option_1"      : "①  시작한 일은 끝까지 해내야 한다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  마음먹었을 때 바로 실천해야 한다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  자신의 한계를 알아야 도전할 수 있다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  고난을 극복하려면 강한 정신력이 필요하다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : I met Kim Dong-jin, who completed the Amazon Jungle Marathon, the most difficult marathon. Why did you make such a difficult challenge?\nMan : I went to the Amazon because I wanted to test my limits. The number of people who have completed the jungle marathon is one of the best. The physical and mental pain there was indescribable, but the joy and emotion I felt at that time was irreplaceable. But there's something I think I did better than finishing the race. It was action when something happened that I wanted to challenge. If I hesitated, I wouldn't have been able to challenge myself and I wouldn't have felt this sense of accomplishment.",
      "correctAnswer" : "②  마음먹었을 때 바로 실천해야 한다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     },
     {
     "sections"      : "※ [25~26]다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
      "question"      : "26.들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
      "option_1"      : "①  남자는 정글을 최고의 마라톤 장소로 꼽았다.",
      "option_2"      : "②  남자는 마라톤 선수들을 통해 많은 것을 배웠다.",
      "option_3"      : "③  남자는 고통이 심해서 마라톤을 중간에 포기했다.",
      "option_4"      : "④  남자는 아마존에서 자신의 의지를 시험하고 싶었다.",
      "detail"        : "Woman : I met Kim Dong-jin, who completed the Amazon Jungle Marathon, the most difficult marathon. Why did you make such a difficult challenge?\nMan : I went to the Amazon because I wanted to test my limits. The number of people who have completed the jungle marathon is one of the best. The physical and mental pain there was indescribable, but the joy and emotion I felt at that time was irreplaceable. But there's something I think I did better than finishing the race. It was action when something happened that I wanted to challenge. If I hesitated, I wouldn't have been able to challenge myself and I wouldn't have felt this sense of accomplishment.",
      "correctAnswer" : "④  남자는 아마존에서 자신의 의지를 시험하고 싶었다.",
      "score"         : "2"
     }
    ]
}
